# 你在这倒腾什么呢 白菜啊
- What are you making here? - Napa cabbage
# 白菜是什么菜 乾隆白菜
- Napa cabbage made in what way? - Qian Long Napa Cabbage (Qian Long: one of the emperors of the Qing Dynasty)
# 其实我给更正名儿叫乾隆拌菜
Actually I would change its name to Qian Long Cabbage Salad
# 然后你看 芝麻酱
Then you see, (put in) the seasame paste
# 你看啊 糖 糖还不少呢
And sugar, more than just a little
# 不够甜呢就得搁点盐
If it is not sweet enough, add in some salt
# 这菜就是我们公司发明的
This dish is invented by our company
# 这搁点儿香油
A little bit seasame oil
# 原来他们好多人使米醋 这米醋就不对
I've seen quite a few people using rice vinegar, which is not right
# 其实最好是镇江香醋
It's better to use Zhenjiang vinegar
# 这醋都差点儿意思
This one is a bit not as good
# 到底是以甜酸为主还是以咸鲜为主
Does it gonna feature the sweet-n-sour taste or the umami?
# 甜酸咸都有
It has them all
# 还是糖醋为主 糖醋稍微大一点
It's mostly sweet-n-sour. The taste of sugar and vinegar would be a little more prominent
# 爽口
Tasty and refreshing
# 老抽 旁边儿
Dark soy sauce, from the sides
# 你看醋都没上上色 原来为什么拌的颜色不对啊
You see, it has not get the right colour from the vinegar
# 颜色浅 颜色不够
The colour is too mild
# 这色你看还浅
Still mild
# 镇江香醋这颜色一下就提起来了
If you use Zhenjiang vinegar the colour would come out immediately
# 矿泉水啊
Water
# 这就好了点儿 颜色上来了
Now it's better. The colour is emerging
# 还缺一样东西 蜂蜜
We need one more thing - honey
# 甜酸咸 酱香就是麻酱的香气都能吃出来
Sweet, sour, salty, you can even taste the aroma of seasame paste
# 它也是一个复合味
So it has a combo of flavour
# 但您搁蜂蜜我觉得特别巧妙
I think, it is very ingenious of you to add the honey
# 搁这里边
Put in here
# 搅拌均匀
Stir and mix thoroughly
# 我这个不好拌啊 还是放个大家伙里头吧
This one is not handy for mixing. I'd better find a larger container
# 拿那菜擦擦那盆儿
Pick a leaf to wipe the basin
# 老大就是老大啊
I see why you are the first of us
# 不是 因为这汁儿特别好吃
Nah, because this sauce is extremely delicious
# 这一擦 好家伙
Wiping it, gracious me!
# 菜也拌匀了 汁也都擦到菜上了
The veggies are mixed thoroughly with the sauce, and the sauce is sticked to the leaves
# 你看外面那麻酱 那没法吃
You know, the seasame paste they use out there, it is even not edible
# 要味没味 要颜色没颜色
Ain't got no taste or colour
# 白菜有什么要求么
Is there any requirement for the cabbage?
# 您看见没有 全是黄心儿的
Don't you see, the colour is all yellow
# 好白菜 这东西绝对不能糊弄
This is cabbage of quality. You must not muddle with it.
# 这是白菜心儿 叶儿占的比例还比较多
This is the heart of the cabbage. It has a considerable proportion of leaves
# 对 基本上使叶儿是最好的
Yep. Basically it's best to use the leaves
# 来点芝麻啊咱们
Let's get some seasame
# 撒里边就行
Just drop in
# 我觉得啊 这白菜要是搁点黑芝麻更好看
I think, the cabbage would look better with black seasame
# 对啊 那当然是了
Yeah, of course
# 黑芝麻的颜色出来以后这效果好
The colour of black seasame would add to the effects
# 你看 这叫乾隆白菜
You see, this is what we call Qian Long Napa Cabbage
# 这颜色 颜色漂亮 特润
The colour, the colour is so pretty, and looks extremely smooth
# 而且每个叶儿上都均匀的裹上了麻酱
Each leave is evenly wrapped with the seasame paste
# 现在（外边的）乾隆白菜都不对 没错
- Now people out there are not making the right Qian Long Napa Cabbage. - Exactly
# 您还甭说别的 咱看看这个怎么样
No more words, let's see how is this dish
# 看您心情吧 我 看您心情 （哎哟哟哟）心情好
- As you please. - Ohh I AM very pleased (这句的意思实在有点捉摸不透)
# 您看看这个 这拌完这盆儿
Have a look on this basin after the mixing work
# 盆儿干净 不是干净
- It's clear. - Not about being clear or not
# 你看这盆儿 它的酱全挂在这儿
You see, it's all covered with the remnant paste
# 它不是说像那澥得全是水
It's not watery at all, without any superfluous water
# 你说这样它能拌不上么
So the source can definitely stick to the cabbage
# 再点点儿芝麻
A little more seasame
# 星星点点 芝麻酥香 白菜脆嫩
Specks of aromatic seasame with crispy and tender cabbage
# 麻酱润香润香的
The seasame paste is smooth and flavourful
# 0:03:33.580
# 我是大爷